<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Orange Countys Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Robert Mack, a top Real Estate Agent in Irvine, shares his own internal real estate agent training for free. His Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 11:44:48 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 11:44:48 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Speaking to New People Daily?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pPCO-CKXlcs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today I’m sharing how to grow your database and therefore expand your business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you speaking to new people every day? Today I want to discuss building your database. &lt;strong&gt;It’s critical to have a database&lt;/strong&gt; and you should make sure to call and engage with the people in your database. Most of your business should be coming from your database. Your database should make up about 50% to 70% of your business. If it’s not, you may want to review your business and see what you’re doing each day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we continue to grow our database? We’re receiving customer information from multiple different sources. You may be getting contacts from Zillow, Facebook, open house customer inquiries, and so on. You are continually being bombarded with contacts that you don’t know that might need help with real estate. You need to take all this information and regularly add it to your database. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On my team, we have different stages of clients:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stage one:  Someone you’ve never met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stage two:  Someone you’ve had a conversation with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stage three: You’ve met in person, they’re in your database, and they’re now going to be a client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make connections with new clients and maintain them!%20http://localhost:4000/are-you-speaking-to-new-people-daily.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make connections with new clients and maintain them!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expand your database by having new conversations with new people. The beauty of this world is that we’re extremely connected now. Whether it’s on social media (which has steadily become a colossal part of our lives), in line at the grocery store, in church, or anywhere else, our lives are full of opportunities to meet new people. &lt;strong&gt;When you’re in sales, you’re always “on.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most crucial part of the message today is to make connections with new clients and maintain them! The database is essential to any agent’s business. If you’re not on the hunt for new conversations every single day, and you aren’t concentrating your efforts on your database every day, you’re going to have a rough time developing a sustainable business in real estate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to set up a strategy session to learn about the methods we use to build up our database, please reach out to me. Those sessions are free because I enjoy speaking to other agents and learning more about them. If you have any video ideas you want me to talk about in the future, send those my way. If you have any questions about real estate, reach out to me by phone or email. I would be glad to speak with you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 09:07:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-speaking-to-new-people-daily.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-you-speaking-to-new-people-daily.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Value of Your Database</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3skb_uYbn9U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you really understand how important it is to stay in touch with your database? Let’s delve deeper into this topic, today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a strong database is important, but building one up isn’t something every agent takes the time to do. If you’ve been following my content for a while, you probably know that it took me eight or nine years to fully grasp this, myself. Now that I have, I’d like to share what I’ve learned since then with all of you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most crucial lessons to remember on this subject is that &lt;strong&gt;it’s eight times easier to get leads from someone you already know than to get leads from a new business.&lt;/strong&gt; I first learned this from my friend Bill Pipes, a Tom Ferry real estate coach, and keeping this in mind has made an incredible impact on my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Established relationships are a great doorway into new relationships.%20http://localhost:4000/the-value-of-your-database.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Established relationships are a great doorway into new relationships.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t to say that other prospecting methods aren’t effective; only that agents must never underestimate the importance of staying engaged with the people who you know and who have supported you. The people in your database don’t need to be convinced of your skills or experience. They already trust your abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as you can imagine, these established relationships are a great doorway into new relationships. And, &lt;strong&gt;as those new relationships are nurtured, your database (and the opportunities that come from it) will grow exponentially over time.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our team, we make it a priority to connect with our database between 50 and 70 times each year. Whether through phone calls, emails, text messages, or event invites, our team endeavors to let past and present clients know that we are always available as a resource to them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information about nurturing your database, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-value-of-your-database.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-value-of-your-database.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You a “Rock” for Your Clients?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/e0-K9EAWKgw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;As an agent, your buyers and sellers trust you to be a steady source of guidance. Let’s discuss how you can achieve this today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real estate process can be quite overwhelming for buyers and sellers. Emotions run high, expenses can run deep, and energy can run low after days or weeks of striving toward the closing table. This is where you come in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As an agent, part of your job is to advocate for your clients.&lt;/strong&gt; When you work by a buyer or seller’s side, you’re not only bringing your knowledge, experience, and resources to the table, but also a neutral perspective through which they can more clearly assess the deal at hand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you inadvertently put off negative or nervous energy around your client, this can create an unfortunate domino effect. The slightest hint of unease on your end can easily snowball into an emotional meltdown for your clients, who will tend to use you as their “rock.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=To be a rock for your clients, you need to have a mentor who can be yours.%20http://localhost:4000/are-you-a-rock-for-your-clients.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“To be a rock for your clients, you need to have a mentor who can be yours.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you may be thinking that all of this sounds well and good, but feel uncertain as to how you can actually put these concepts into practice. &lt;strong&gt;How can you be a rock for your client? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you need to have a mentor. Whether this mentor is a business coach, a colleague, or a broker, the most important thing is that this person is someone you can trust to be your rock. Your mentor should keep you steady so that you can do the same for your clients. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what if you don’t have a team, broker, or mentor you can turn to?&lt;/strong&gt; If this is the case, please reach out to my team and me. Our team has systems, structures, and training in place to help agents like you succeed at their full potential, and we’d be happy to have a conversation about whether joining us could be the right next move in your career. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 10:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-a-rock-for-your-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-you-a-rock-for-your-clients.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Leverage Social Media to Build Your Brand</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mJ5q4tzGw6E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to grow your business as an agent, now is a great opportunity to leverage social media to get your brand out there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media can be overwhelming for a lot of people, but at the end of the day, that’s the world we live in. So many people communicate via social media, &lt;strong&gt;and the one thing we know about sales is that people want to do business with people they know, like, and trust.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s why it’s important to build an online brand that allows people to get to know you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m personally not a fan of having a business page and a personal page. I believe that, as a real estate agent, people want to work with me—not my brand. They want to work with someone honest, who knows what they’re doing, who they can have fun with, and who they can have a great experience with. Social media is a casual platform to let people know who I am. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key mistake a lot of agents make is constantly talking about business. Buyers, sellers, and anyone else following you don’t necessarily care about your newest listing. They want to know more about you. My rule of thumb is to keep about 60% of my social media personal and 30% business-related. I want them to know who I am—a real estate agent working on doing great things for great people. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Now is a great opportunity to leverage social media to get your brand out there.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-leverage-social-media-to-build-your-brand.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Now is a great opportunity to leverage social media to get your brand out there.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, you have to craft your social media according to who you are. Document what you’re passionate about in your personal life because people want to relate to you on a personal level. Similarly, when talking about business, instead of talking about what you just sold, share the stories you’ve witnessed. People love stories, and they want relatable stories. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, in July I created an Instagram story for a client of mine. This client was a first-time buyer who didn’t have a lot of money and was generally terrified of the home buying experience. However, she connected with the right lender, got a great grant, and was able to buy her condo with just $8,000 out of pocket. Afterward, 38 people reached out to me saying if they could buy a home for the same price she bought hers, they’d love to know more about how to do so. People felt comfortable with me, they fell in love with my story, and they wanted to learn more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So moving forward, embrace social media and let people into your life. Show them what you like to do outside of business, but also talk to them about how you help people in your professional life. &lt;strong&gt;Don’t just talk about how many homes you sold last year; talk about the lives you changed.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s what will draw them in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about how to step up your social media game, give me a call or send me a message. If you’d like to know more about how we do business or you’re looking to align yourself with the Robert Mack Group, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’d love to hear from you. As always, happy selling!&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-leverage-social-media-to-build-your-brand.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-leverage-social-media-to-build-your-brand.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Invest in Yourself and Be a Better Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JispptY9Pck?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the difference between someone who invests in themselves and someone who doesn’t?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer this question, let’s move away from real estate for a second. If you look at how a professional athlete spends their year, about 90% of their time is devoted to practicing—i.e., finding ways to be better. They’re in the gym and working on their diet so they can be as strong as possible and have the highest energy levels. They’re running the same plays thousands of times so when it’s game time, they’re ready to go. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, on the other hand, they just go out and play the game, will they be able to run the plays correctly, or have the endurance to last the entire match? Probably not. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an agent, you need to use the same philosophy. &lt;strong&gt;If you just come into the office with no practice, structure, or strategy and try to do your job, you won’t find yourself among the top 3% of agents nationwide.&lt;/strong&gt; You have to spend 90% of your time practicing, whether that means practicing role-playing scripts, listing presentations, buyer presentations, etc. When you meet with a client face to face, it’s game time. You want to win these “matches,” and if you’re not practicing on the back end, you’re practicing on your clients. If that’s the case, you’re probably not converting at a high level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you meet with a client face to face, it’s game time.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-invest-in-yourself-and-be-a-better-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you meet with a client face to face, it’s game time.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ask yourself, do you have a business coach or team leader who can be your mentor? Are you masterminding with other agents? Are you attending events and learning more about the real estate industry? Are you taking continuing education classes or subscribing to important market newsletters? Do you understand what it takes to be a great agent in today’s industry instead of the one from 10 years ago?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being a real estate professional requires an immense amount of knowledge&lt;/strong&gt;—not just about what’s happening now, but also about what’s happened in the past and what’s anticipated for the future. You need to use the most up-to-date systems and strategies to help your clients at the deepest level, and surrounding yourself with talented individuals will help you create your vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn how to be a better agent or you’re looking for a mentor, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to know more about where you are and where you want to be. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other questions or there’s anything else I can assist you with, feel free to give me a call as well. I look forward to speaking with you. Until then, happy selling!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-invest-in-yourself-and-be-a-better-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-invest-in-yourself-and-be-a-better-agent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What It Takes to Become a Top-3% Realtor</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GayA_ENwpJk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I have some real estate industry statistics to share with you so you can understand where you sit among your competition. I was at a Tom Ferry event last week where he discussed a surprising statistic for real estate agents both globally and in our local market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, there are 1.7 million Realtors in this country. Of them, only 43,000 were able to sell 25 homes or more. That’s just 2.5%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re selling 25 homes or more each year, then you’re in the top 3% of Realtors nationwide—congratulations!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the numbers shift a bit here in Orange County. There are over 16,000 agents here, but only 400 sold 10 or more homes. That’s also the top 2.5%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re selling 10 or more homes per year here in Orange County, congratulations to you.&lt;/strong&gt; You’re in the top 3%, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We have a strong structure, systems, and great admin staff.%20http://localhost:4000/what-it-takes-to-become-a-top-3-realtor.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We have a strong structure, systems, and great admin staff.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I’m sharing this with you is that the other 97% of agents are struggling. These agents need help, they’re winging it, and doing their best to keep their heads above water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can you do to position yourself to be in this top 3% if you aren’t? For starters, you need to start treating real estate like a business. &lt;strong&gt;You need to be committed daily by generating leads, showing homes, and getting deals done.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a solo agent and desire to build a business that’s thriving, you simply can’t do it on your own. You need to align yourself with talented individuals that will take you and your business to another level. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is what we offer at The Robert Mack Group.&lt;/strong&gt; We have a strong structure, complete with systems, great admin staff, and other full-time agents that you can align yourself with and learn from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how our team operates or how you might be able to elevate your career by joining us, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 07:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-it-takes-to-become-a-top-3-realtor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-it-takes-to-become-a-top-3-realtor.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One Agent’s Journey That Began By Learning From the Ground Up</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cTEv_BoqPFg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been tuning into my recent videos, you know that my mission is to offer guidance, mentoring, and tips and tricks to help you and others in the community become better agents. To that end, today I’ve brought on fellow agent Ryan McMillian to talk about his experiences since joining my team and as someone who was in hospitality for over a decade, what it’s been like to reinvent himself professionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ryan was in the restaurant and bar business for just over 11 years before deciding he wanted to break into the real estate industry.&lt;/strong&gt; So, he completed his classes and earned his license to practice. As a new licensee, he wasn’t sure what his next step should be, but he knew he wanted to be part of a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He got in touch with a few different teams and brokerages, and in the process, he met me. Thanks to his previous experience, Ryan had developed strong interpersonal skills and had a knack for customer service, but he knew that above all finding a mentor would be his key to success in real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;During our conversation, I assured Ryan that I would teach him the practices and systems that would mold him into a great agent over time&lt;/strong&gt;, but I also let him know in no uncertain terms he’d be required to learn from the ground up. This was refreshing to Ryan: He was skeptical of other brokerages he spoke with because they attempted to persuade him with unrealistic claims that he’d have instant success and wealth working for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not long after, the two of us arranged another meeting and we discussed what it would take for Ryan to become a great agent—a decision Ryan says he’s glad he made. &lt;strong&gt;Being part of our team has allowed him to grow his business far beyond what he believes he could have accomplished on his own.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=As daunting as it may seem, becoming a great agent is possible and Ryan’s story is evidence of that.%20http://localhost:4000/one-agents-journey-that-began-by-learning-from-the-ground-up.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“As daunting as it may seem, becoming a great agent is possible and Ryan’s story is evidence of that.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got into the business back in 2006, real estate teams were the exception, rather than the rule. In fact, I didn’t really know what a mentor was, and I didn’t have the money to hire a business coach. I was mostly left to fend for myself and learn through trial and error what worked and what didn’t. Though I had a solid family and friend base to help me get my start, my first six to eight years were a grind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, as I’ve built my team and fine-tuned our systems and strategies, I’ve gained an abundance of experience helping buyers, sellers, and investors as well as an understanding of what it takes to become a great agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a newly licensed agent or you’re in the process of earning your license and you’re watching this, we can’t emphasize enough how tough this industry is. The failure rate is right around 90%, and if you don’t have a mentor looking out for you in the early stages of your career, your likelihood of success is significantly lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As daunting as it may seem, becoming a great agent is possible and Ryan’s story is evidence of that.&lt;/strong&gt; Beyond leveraging his relationship-building skills, Ryan needed to learn the fundamentals of the business—how to show homes, write offers, help sellers, negotiate commissions, negotiate on behalf of his buyers, and the list goes on. All in all, Ryan’s decision to become part of our team couldn’t have worked out better for us or him, and we’re grateful he’s with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In closing, if you’re currently or about to be an agent and you’re wondering what your next step should be, Ryan and I would love to have a conversation with you, so don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to answer any of your questions or set up a strategy call with you today! Until then, happy selling!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/one-agents-journey-that-began-by-learning-from-the-ground-up.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/one-agents-journey-that-began-by-learning-from-the-ground-up.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Follow-Up Is So Important to Your Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jKudWbif1PI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a newer agent or one who is building their business or a veteran agent who is looking to set yourself apart, you need to pay attention to follow-up. &lt;strong&gt;Once you have a database, and as you learn how to add people to it, follow-up becomes extremely important.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not about just making one phone call and hoping for the best. It’s about nurturing a relationship over time, building trust, earning business, and closing the sale. &lt;strong&gt;Here’s a short story from my experience that might put things into perspective:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in the market to buy a new car, but I hadn’t bought one in a long time. I became a lead and I wanted a Toyota 4 Runner. &lt;strong&gt;I sent an email out to 10 different dealerships asking them all the same questions. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a lot of automated responses, I got a lot of people who followed up with one email, and other people had manual custom emails from the start. I went back and forth with a few different salesmen until I narrowed it down to three. &lt;strong&gt;I based my decision on the quality of content they sent me, how authentic I felt their emails were, how much value they brought in those emails, and the quantity of their follow-up.&lt;/strong&gt; At the end, I had a phone conversation with all three finalists. It was a nice lesson for me as an agent. Sometimes you have to work an email until you can get in touch with a person. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my phone conversations, I got their pricing, and ultimately one salesman stood out. I went in and was out within an hour and a half with my new car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You can’t just call a lead once and expect them to buy in.%20http://localhost:4000/why-follow-up-is-so-important-to-your-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You can’t just call a lead once and expect them to buy in.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have to understand that buying a home is a huge decision for someone.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a massive commitment and a lot of buyers are scared and nervous, but excited. That’s exactly how I felt when I got my new car. It’s important to keep those emotions in mind, because if you don’t have empathy, you will lose. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above and beyond the empathy, you also have to understand that our leads are talking to more than one agent. &lt;strong&gt;If you reach out once, you’re wasting your time.&lt;/strong&gt; What should you do to follow up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Send mailers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Door knock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invite them to an event&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Send texts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Send videos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reach out through social media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Call them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On our team, we average about nine touches per prospect until we get a contract signed.&lt;/strong&gt; They can include any and all of the above. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moral of the story here is that if you’re getting leads and referrals, you can’t just call them once and expect them to buy in. You need to consistently follow up and offer value. &lt;strong&gt;We don’t just check in—we contact our prospects and offer value at the same time.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s so important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me in the future, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 10:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-follow-up-is-so-important-to-your-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-follow-up-is-so-important-to-your-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Do to Build Your Database?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ThXheUh-K5Y?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an agent, your database is vitally important to the continued success of your career. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a frame of reference: &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0% of the homes we sell on a yearly basis come from our database.&lt;/strong&gt; Our database includes our friends and family, past coworkers, other professionals in the industry, vendors, past clients, other agents in other areas, etc. I’m constantly looking for ways to grow my database by talking to new people every single day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can you do to build and grow your database?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are tons of different databases out there to choose from. Don’t get caught up on which one is the best. Just get one you’ll use, and the simplest one is probably your best option. Just have a place where you can store emails, phone numbers, addresses, names, and other relevant information. Also, make sure it’s a place where you can write notes and task reminders about your clients in a timely manner. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your friends and family know you sell real estate, but the fortune in this business is found in the follow-up.&lt;/strong&gt; Your clients won’t always be thinking about you, and they won’t always think to call you if they have a need. They’ll call the first person they think of, but if you haven’t positioned yourself as the professional agent in their life, you won’t get that call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you add people to your database and stay in touch with them, you will make money—I guarantee it.%20http://localhost:4000/what-can-you-do-to-build-your-database.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you add people to your database and stay in touch with them, you will make money—I guarantee it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you how many of my close friends never ended up calling me to help them buy or sell a home because they assumed I was too busy for them. That shouldn’t be happening to you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So find a database you’ll use (you’ll probably have to spend a little bit of money) and add your friends and family, past coworkers, your current and past clients, and anyone else you pay money to. My hairstylist is in my database—so is my mechanic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You need to grow your database every single day.&lt;/strong&gt; On my team, our goal is to grow our database by five to 10 individuals each day. How do I find these people? There are a variety of ways. They could be random connections at the grocery store. They could be the result of cold calling or expired listings. In any case, you should always be collecting data, and every time someone reaches out to you because they want to buy a home, they go into your database. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you stay in touch with your database? We have a 55-point marketing plan, meaning we “touch” our clients at least 55 times per year through email, text, direct mail, newsletters, etc. If you don’t have a lot of money at your disposal, though, I think at a minimum you should do a monthly newsletter. Focus more on who’s getting that newsletter on a monthly basis rather than the content of that newsletter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you add people to your database and stay in touch with them, you will make money—I guarantee it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to learn more about building your database or you’re thinking of joining a new team, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you. Until them, keep selling houses! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 09:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-can-you-do-to-build-your-database.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-can-you-do-to-build-your-database.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Off the Entrepreneurial Roller Coaster</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/koDED4uX6Yw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When new agents finally break into the industry, their success is determined by the number of conversations they have with people they can develop relationships with, and who, over time, they can help buy, sell, or invest in real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to be a great Realtor, you have to have a lot of conversations with people about the services you offer. &lt;strong&gt;If you have four or five of these conversations a day, in two or three months, those interactions will lead to clients.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that when these agents spend so much time making phone calls, sending texts, and attending networking events, they get busy helping clients find and sell properties and stop having these important conversations altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your business becomes an entrepreneurial roller coaster once you’ve stopped doing what’s necessary to maintain a pipeline full of prospects. It’s at that point that your business starts to fail, causing you to panic and revert back to making phone calls and networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your business becomes an entrepreneurial roller coaster once you’ve stopped doing what’s necessary to maintain a pipeline full of prospects.%20http://localhost:4000/getting-off-the-entrepreneurial-roller-coaster.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your business becomes an entrepreneurial roller coaster once you’ve stopped doing what’s necessary to maintain a pipeline full of prospects.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can you do to avoid this roller coaster business style? &lt;strong&gt;Here are three suggestions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Hire someone to help you with the paperwork.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether that entails hiring an administrative assistant, a transaction coordinator, or working with a virtual assistant, you need to find someone to take some of the work off your plate so that you can focus on higher-level activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Consider joining a team.&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of successful teams in Orange County already have the administrative help on the back end. As an agent on a team, you can leverage the admin assistant to help you close more transactions and focus on keeping up with your pipeline and prospects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Work longer hours.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re not willing to hire help or find a team with, then unfortunately, you’ll just have to work longer hours. However, don’t stop prospecting altogether—if you do, you’ll be stuck in the roller coaster once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re struggling to get off the entrepreneurial roller coaster and would like to set up a strategy session with me, please feel free to reach out. I’d love to help you figure out how we can help your business grow in a sustainable way. Until then, happy selling!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 10:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/getting-off-the-entrepreneurial-roller-coaster.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/getting-off-the-entrepreneurial-roller-coaster.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
